Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Western Medicine, 1966-1968 (Box 69)
  - WGBH (TV), 1983 (Box 69)
  - Whitehead, Bill, 1974-1976 (Box 69)
  - The White House, 1977-1978; 1981 (Box 69)
  - Whitman, Kenneth J., 1976 (Box 69)
  - Whittier Law Review, 1985 (Box 69)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1985; outgoing only (Box 69)
  - Wilcox, Lee, 1980-1981 (Box 69)
  - Wilcox, Lynn, 1971; 1976-1980,; 1986,; undated; 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Williams, John R., 1977-1979 (Box 69)
  - Williams, Tennessee, 1976; outgoing only (Box 69)
  - Windholz, Emanuel, 1956 (Box 69)
  - Windholz, George, 1984-1986 (Box 69)
  - Winthrop, Henry, 1962; 1967 (Box 69)
  - Wisdom Hall of Fame, 1970 (Box 69)
  - Wise, Louis and Christine, 1954; 1969 (Box 70)
  - Wiseman, Frederick, 1974 (Box 70)
  - Witkin, Jerome, 1992; undated (Box 70)
  - Wolf, Popper, Ross, Wolf & Jones, 1966; 1970 (Box 70)
  - Wolfram, Neil S., 1975; 1981 (Box 70)
  - Wolman, Benjamin B., 1973-1974 (Box 70)
  - Woloshin, Arthur A., 1956-1957; 1960 (Box 70)
  - Women's Economic Club, 1969-1970 (Box 70)
  - Wood, Charles A., 1977-1979; undated (Box 70)
  - Woodger, J.H., 1957-1958 (Box 70)
  - Wooster, John J., 1955; 1961 (Box 70)
  - Wootton, Barbara, 1962-1965; 1969-1973 (Box 70)
  - World Federation of Doctors Who Respect Human Life, 1981 (Box 70)
  - World Health Organization (WHO), 1946; 1948,; 1955,; 1958,; 1976,; 1980; includes publications (Box 70)
    See also Velimirovic, Boris.
  - World Wide Features, 1969 (Box 70)
  - Wortham, Anne, 1976-1977 (Box 70)
  - WSYR, 1973 (Box 70)
  - Wyatt, Randall, 2001 (Box 70)
  - W, miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 70)
  - Yagman, Stephen, 1982-1983 (Box 70)
  - Yale Review, 1959-1961; 1965,; 1969,; 1972 (Box 70)
  - Yale University, 1961-1962; 1969,; 1977 (Box 70)
  - Yeshuran, Shraga, 1955 (Box 70)
  - Yoder, C. Rodney, 2000-2003; undated (Box 71)
  - Young, Frank, 1980 (Box 71)
  - Young, Kathleen, 1990 (Box 71)
  - Ypsilanti State Hospital, 1063-1965 (Box 71)
  - Yurick, Sol, 1966; 1970 (Box 71)
  - Zahar Editores, 1974-1977 (Box 71)
  - Zeley, Laszlo, 1981; 1993 (Box 71)
    See also Magyar Radio.
  - Zinberg, Norman E., 1969-1970 (Box 71)
  - Zopf, Michael, 1983 (Box 71)
  - Zwirn, Irving, 1960-1961 (Box 71)
  - X, Y, Z miscellaneous (Box 71)
  - First name only (Box 71)
  - Unidentified (Box 71)
- Financial
  - Bills, 1974-1977; 6 folders (Box 72)
  - Royalties
    - Aldine Publishing Company, 1966-1971 (Box 72)
    - Alfred A. Knopf Inc., 1974-1976; 1981-1982,; 1986 (Box 72)
    - Amboboeken, 1972-1975; 1978 (Box 72)
    - Armando Armando Editore, 1977-1981; 1987-1990,; 1992,; 2006 (Box 72)
    - Basic Books, Inc., 1961-1989; 2001; 3 folders (Box 72)
    - Bokforlags AB Alba, 1978-1988 (Box 72)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1983 (Box 72)
    - Calder & Boyars, 1973; 1975-1981 (Box 72)
    - Copyright Clearance Center, Inc., 1997-1998; 2000,; 2004 (Box 72)
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1968-1989; 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Edicions Martinez Roca, S.A., 1992-1995 (Box 73)
    - Editions Payot, 1973; 1975-1984,; 1987-1993 (Box 73)
    - Editorial Gredos, S.A., 1969; 1971,; 1979,; 1981-1982,; 1986 (Box 73)
    - Editorial Kairos, 1973; 1978,; 1981,; 1985,; 1988,; 1990,; 1997,; 2006-2008 (Box 73)
    - Editorial Premia, 1978-1980 (Box 73)
    - Europa Verlag, 1974-1986 (Box 73)
    - Feltrinelli Editore, 1971; 1973-1982,; 1986,; 1988-1991,; 1993 (Box 73)
    - Fischer Taschenbuch, 1978-1983 (Box 73)
    - Greenwood Publishing Group Inc., 1998-2008 (Box 73)
    - Giuffre Editore Milano, 1985-1986; 1991,; 1995 (Box 73)
    - Harper Collins Publishers, 1990-2008; 3 folders (Box 73)
    - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1961-1975 (Box 73)
    - Harper & Row, Publishers, Inc., 1961-1989; undated; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1980-1983 (Box 74)
    - John Wiley & Sons Inc., 1994-1997 (Box 74)
    - Learning Publications Inc., 1998-2002 (Box 74)
    - Louisiana State University Press, 1976-1989 (Box 74)
    - MacMillan Publishing Co., Inc., 1962-1994; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Marion Boyars Publishers Ltd., 1982-1994; 2005,; 2007 (Box 74)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1969-1973 (Box 74)
    - Open Court Publishing Co., 1999-2001; 2003-2005 (Box 74)
    - Oxford University Press, 1979; 1983-1984 (Box 74)
    - Perseus Books Group, 1998-2001; 2003-2007 (Box 74)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1959-1962 (Box 74)
    - Presses Universitaires de France, 1976-1994; 2004 (Box 74)
    - Publicações dom Quixote, 1976; 1978,; 1979,; 1982 (Box 74)
    - The Reader's Digest, 1975; 1977,; 1982,; 1985-1986 (Box 74)
    - Routledge & Kegan Paul Ltd., 1972-1986 (Box 74)
    - Shinsen-Sha, 1980-1991; 1983-1984,; 1992 (Box 90)
    - Syracuse University Press, 1998-2007; 2 folders (Box 90)
    - Transaction Books, 2002-2007 (Box 90)
    - Tusquets Editores, 1978-1992 (Box 90)
    - The University of Chicago Press, 1962-1980 (Box 90)
    - Walter-Verlag, 1975-1982 (Box 90)
    - Zahar Editors, 1977-1978; 1981,; 1984 (Box 90)
    - Ziff-Davis Publishing Company, 1978-1980 (Box 90)
    - Miscellaneous A-Z (Box 90)
  - Taxes, 1998-1999; 2001,; 2003; 4 folders (Box 90)
  - Trust funds, 1968-1972 (Box 90)
- Memorabilia
  - Artwork
    - By others, 1977; 2005; drawings of Szasz (Box 91)
    - By Margot Szasz, 1970 (Box 91)
    - Portraits and caricatures of Szasz (Oversize 6)
    - "Ehre den vergessern Opfern" bronze plaque rubbing (Tube 1)
      Handmade rubbing of a bronze plaque commemorating the 200,000 victims of "Aktion T4," Germany's program of euthanasia for those deemed mentally or physically "unworthy." Those involved in carrying out the program included "scientists, doctors, nurses, policemen and law, health and work officials." The original is embedded in the ground near Robert Serra's "Berlin Junction" sculpture in Tiergartenstrasse in Berlin.
  - Awards, arranged alphabetically by awarding body; includes certificates of appreciation, honorary degrees, etc.
    - The Academy of Humanism, 1973; clippings about award (Box 91)
    - The Academy of Humanism, 1985; plaque (Box 92)
    - Allegheny College, 1975; honorary degree; includes photos; 2 folders (Box 91)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Medical Society, 1944 (Oversize 5)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), New York Chapter, 1967; Ralph E. Kharas Award (Oversize 5)
    - American Humanist Association, 1973; Humanist of the Year (Oversize 2)
    - American Institute for Public Service, 1974 (Oversize 2)
    - American Psychiatric Association, 1956; 1983,; 2003; certificates for Fellow, Life Fellow, Distinguished Life Fellow (Box 91)
    - American Psychiatric Association "Life Fellow" (Oversize 1)
    - American Psychoanalytic Association, 1951; 1983; certificates for Active Member, Life Member (Box 91)
    - American Psychological Association, 1998; plaque (Box 92)
    - Church of Scientology, 1992 (Oversize 1)
    - Citizens Commission on Human Rights, 1994 (Oversize 1)
    - Citizens Commission on Human Rights 35th Anniversary, 2004 (Box 91)
    - Criminologia.it, 2008; medal (Box 91)
    - The Drug Policy Foundation, 1991; 1996; Alfred R. Lindesmith Award for scholarship and writing; 2 folders (Box 91)
    - The Drug Policy Foundation, 1991; plaque (Box 92)
    - Evolution of Psychotherapy, 1995 (Oversize 2)
    - Free Press Association, 1981; plaque (Box 92)
    - "From his friends and admirers", 1990 (Oversize 2)
    - Great Lakes Association of Clinical Medicine, 1995; plaque (Box 93)
    - Harvard Medical School, 1990; Norman E. Zinsburg lecturer (Box 91)
    - Horizon House, 1985 (Oversize 1)
    - The International Academy of Forensic Psychology, 1969; Fellow (Box 91)
    - International Federation for Psychoanalytic Education, 2002; plaque (Box 93)
    - Lambie Dew Oration, 1977 (Oversize 1)
    - Law-Science Academy of America, 1959; elected to membership (Oversize 5)
    - The Little Synagogue Mid-way Counseling Center, 1974; Martin Buber Award (Box 91)
    - The National Register of Prominent Americans, 1974-1975; Member of Eminent Distinction (Box 91)
    - Der Ordensrat des Verbandes nationalgesinnter Soldaten (Oversize 5)
    - SUNY Upstate Medical Center (Oversize 1)
    - SUNY Upstate Medical University, 2001; honorary degree; 2 folders (Box 91)
    - Templeton Foundations Honor Roll, 1989 (Oversize 5)
    - The Thomas S. Szasz Award, 1998; Spelled "Szaz"; awarded to Robert D. Kephart (Box 91)
    - Towson University, 1999; honorary degree (Oversize 7)
    - Universidad Francisco Marroquin, 1979; honorary degree, illuminated on parchment (Oversize 6)
    - University of California, San Francisco, 1972; Certificate of Appreciation (Box 91)
    - University of Cincinnati College of Medicine, 1944; Stella Feiss Hoffheimer Memorial Prize (Oversize 5)
    - Wisdom Society, 1970; Wisdom Award of Honor (Oversize 5)
    - Wisdom Hall of Fame, 1970; 1988 (Box 91)
    - Miscellaneous, TS, 1986; 1987,; 2002,; undated; nominations, brochures, etc. related to foundations Szasz is involved in (Box 91)
    - Miscellaneous, others, 1971; undated; awards received by Lily, Suzy, and Margot (Box 91)
    - Miscellaneous medals (Oversize 2)
  - Conferences and symposiums
    - Asclepius at Syracuse: Thomas Szasz, Libertarian Humanist, 1980; 4 folders (Box 94)
      See also Photographs: Professional: Asclepius Symposium and Posters: Asclepius Symposium below.
    - The Ditchley Foundation Conference on Psychiatry and the Law, 1970-1972; guest of honor (Box 94)
    - Liberty and/or Psychiatry? 40 Years After the Myth of Mental Illness, 2000; symposium in honor of Szasz's 80th birthday
      - Program, letters, correspondence, etc., 3 folders (Box 94)
      - Guest book and photos (Box 95)
      - Photo album (Oversize 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1950; 1959-1985,; 1986-1990,; 1998,; 2001; brochures, fliers, programs, clippings, etc.; 7 folders (Box 95)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; brochures, fliers, programs, clippings, etc. (Box 96)
  - Education
    - Szasz, Margot, 1959-1979 (Box 96)
    - Szasz, Suzy, 1960-1972 (Box 96)
    - Szasz, Thomas, 1940-1949; undated; 2 folders (Box 96)
    - Szasz, Thomas, 1941; University of Cincinnati, BA degree with honors in physics (Oversize 6)
  - Father's death (Julius Szasz), 1962 (Box 96)
  - Grant application, Van Ameringen Foundation, 1984-1993; 2 folders (Box 96)
  - Handwriting analysis, undated (Box 96)
  - Identification documents, passports, driver's licenses, etc.
    - Szasz, Thomas, 1920-1990; undated (Box 96)
    - Others, 1903; 1908,; 1913,; 1953,; 1970,; 1975,; 1981 (Box 96)
  - Inscriptions, 1994; photocopies of pages from books and guest books signed/inscribed to Szasz (Box 97)
  - Legal documents
    - Hungary, 1896-1959; 2 folders (Box 97)
    - Medical registrations, 1954; 1965-1966,; 1973,; 1982-1987 (Box 97)
    - Naturalization, US, 1938-1944; 1956 (Box 97)
    - Vehicle, 1952-1958 (Box 97)
  - Louis Wain postcards (Box 97)
  - Medical degrees, certificates, and licenses, 1944-1947; 1950-1952,; 1956; medicine, surgery, psychiatry, psychoanalysis (Oversize 7)
  - Medical licenses, 1949; 1954,; 1991-1992; medicine, surgery (Box 97)
  - Medical school graduation, 1944; commencement program, letters of congratulation (Box 97)
  - Military records, 1949-1957; 1994; includes commission as Lieutenant in Medical Corps, honorable discharge, etc.; 2 folders (Box 97)
  - Notebooks, content unknown, mostly numbers; 2 volumes (Box 97)
  - Photographs
    - Family
      - George Szasz, 1946; undated (Box 98)
      - Margot Szasz, 1953; 1954,; 1960-1967,; 1969,; 1982,; undated; 2 folders (Box 98)
      - Rosine Szasz, 1948; 1949,; 1955,; 1969,; undated (Box 98)
      - Suzy Szasz, 1962-1969; 1973,; 1981,; 1982,; undated (Box 98)
      - Suzy Szasz, framed wedding photos; 2 items (Oversize 5)
      - Thomas Szasz, 1924; 1926,; 1938,; 1952,; 1956-1962,; 1969-1972,; 1975-1976,; 1980-1981,; 1992-1993,; undated; 5 folders (Box 98)
      - Thomas Szasz, includes formal portraits, group school photos (Oversize 5)
      - Miscellaneous, small photo album (Oversize 5)
      - Miscellaneous, formal portraits of a man and a woman, possibly Szasz's parents (Oversize 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1948; 1955-1983,; 1988-1997,; 2001,; 2005,; undated; 10 folders (Box 99)
      - Miscellaneous, 2001-2007; undated; 2 folders (Box 100)
    - Professional
      - Asclepius Symposium, 1980; 2 folders (Box 100)
      - Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference, 1990; 1995; 2 folders (Box 100)
      - Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference, 2000; photo album (Box 101)
      - Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference, 1985; 1990,; 1995,; 2000 (Oversize 5)
      - Hawaii, 1984; 1986,; 1990; unidentified conference (Box 101)
      - Portrait, 1992 (Box 101)
      - University of Cincinnati Medical School class photo, 1944 (Oversize 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950; 1961-1964,; 1968-1974,; 1981-1985,; undated; 3 folders (Box 101)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1947; 1955-1956,; 1962,; 1968-1973,; 1977,; 1980-1986,; 1990-1991,; 1994-1995,; 1999-2001,; undated; 4 folders (Box 102)
    - Travel
      - Albany, NY, 1980 (Box 102)
      - Anchorage, AK, 1980 (Box 102)
      - [Budapest?], undated (Box 102)
      - Canada/Niagara, 1973 (Box 102)
      - Chittenango, NY, undated (Box 102)
      - Colorado, 1979; 1983 (Box 102)
      - Egypt, undated (Box 102)
      - Hawaii/California, 1972 (Box 102)
      - Hong Kong, undated (Box 102)
        See also Japan photographs, below.
      - Italy, 1975; 1984,; undated (Box 102)
      - Japan, 1975; undated; 3 folders (Box 102)
        Some of these appear to be from Hong Kong, but were filed all together in an envelope labeled "Japan."
      - Lake George & Europe[?], 1982; undated (Box 102)
      - [Maine or Canada?], undated (Box 102)
      - Mt. Rainier, 1972 (Box 103)
      - [Nice, France?], undated (Box 103)
      - South Africa, 1970 (Box 103)
      - [Switzerland?], 1985; undated (Box 103)
      - Switzerland/Australia, 1981; 1982 (Box 103)
      - Miscellaneous, 1939; 1987,; 1993,; 1994,; 1997,; undated; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous
      - BJ, 1973; 1977,; undated (Box 103)
      - Cartoons, glass slides (Oversize 8)
      - Cartoons for books, undated; slides (Box 103)
      - Lynn Wilcox, 1971; undated (Box 103)
      - Mounted reproductions, mix of formal and family photos, enlarged and mounted; possibly used as a display for some event; 17 items (Oversize 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1890; 1900,; 1917,; 1922,; 1937,; 1939,; 1946,; 1954-1955,; 1963,; 1974-1975,; 1981-1982,; 1996,; undated; 4 folders (Box 103)
      - Miscellaneous people (Oversize 5)
  - Postcards, 1941; 1945,; undated (Box 104)
  - Posters
    - "Asclepius at Syracuse" sign, 1980 (Map-case 102)
    - "Evolution of Psychotherapy," signed by participants, 1994 (Tube 1)
    - "Evolution of Psychotherapy," signed by participants, 1995 (Map-case 102)
    - "Exiles from [Germany]", photos and brief bios; among those featured are Freud, Einstein, and one Otto Szasz (Oversize 7)
    - Szasz appearances, miscellaneous, conferences, symposia, lectures, author appearances, debates, etc., mostly in the U.S. but a few overseas (Oversize 7)
  - Printed material
    - About Thomas Szasz
      - Lists of articles about Szasz (Box 104)
      - Articles, 1962-1995; 2000,; 2002,; 2005,; 2011; journals and magazines; 5 folders (Box 104)
      - Clippings, 1950-1962; newspapers; 2 folders (Box 104)
      - Clippings, 1963 (Oversize 4)
      - Clippings, 1963-1971 Jul; 7 folders (Box 105)
      - Clippings, 1971 Aug-1974; 4 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Clippings, 1971 Oct-1974 Jul; 8 folders (Box 106)
      - Clippings, 1974 Dec-1979 Jun; 9 folders (Box 107)
      - Clippings, 1975; 1977; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Clippings, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Clippings, 1979 Jul-1993; 8 folders (Box 108)
      - Clippings, 1982; 1993; 2 folders (Oversize 4)
      - Clippings, 1994-2010; 7 folders (Box 109)
      - Clippings, undated; 4 folders (Box 109)
      - Clippings, undated (Box 110)
      - Clippings, undated; framed page from "SUNY Voices" (Oversize 4)
      - Reprints, 1968-1969; 1973,; 1976 (Box 110)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962; 1969-1972,; 1975,; 1979,; 1983 (Box 110)
    - About Margot Szasz
      - Clippings, 1959; 1966,; 1968,; 1971 (Box 110)
    - About Suzy Szasz
      - Clippings, 1964-1965; 1989,; undated (Box 110)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958; 1962,; 1971,; 1991,; 1995,; 1998,; 2002,; 2006,; undated; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 10)
  - Resurrection of Hungary by Griffith Arthur, inscribed to Szasz by Eda Sagarra, 1904; 1995 (Box 110)
  - Souvenir issue of New York Times from April 15, 1920 (Szasz's birthday) (Oversize 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1979-1980; clippings (Box 110)
  - Travel, receipts, souvenirs, tickets, etc., arranged chronologically by date of trip; titles given below are transcribed from original folders or envelopes, the meanings are not always clear
    See also Photographs: Travel, above.
    - South Africa, Sep 1970 (Box 111)
    - Australia, Feb 11, 1956; Jun 23 and 27, 1977;; Jul 27-Aug 15, 1977 (Box 111)
    - Italy, Jul-Aug 1985 (Box 111)
    - Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference, 1985; 3 folders (Box 111)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985; 5 folders (Box 111)
    - Australia, Jul 24-Aug 10, 1986 (Box 111)
    - Honolulu, Oct 30, 1986 (Box 111)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986; 6 folders (Box 112)
    - London, Jul 20, 1988 (Box 112)
    - London, Jul 1988 (Box 112)
    - Brussels, Sep 28, 1988 (Box 112)
    - New York, Oct 4, 1988 (Box 112)
    - Oregon, Oct 26-27, 1988 (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988; 2 folders (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988; 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Firing Line, Jan 15, 1996 (Box 113)
    - CCHR, Feb 15, 1996 (Box 113)
    - San Antonio, Feb 28-Mar 1, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Tenerife, Mar 10-16, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Saint Michael's College, Mar 1996 (Box 113)
    - CH, Apr 1996 (Box 113)
    - Washington, DC, Apr 23-24, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Brazil, May 1996 (Box 113)
    - Buffalo, Jun 1, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Newcastle, Jun 20, 1996 (Box 113)
    - Brussels, Jun 1996 (Box 113)
    - Vienna, Jul 5-9, 1996; 3 folders (Box 113)
    - Storm, Sep 1998 (Box 113)
    - Erickson, May 24, 2000 (Box 113)
    - Evolution of Psychotherapy Conference Anaheim, CA, May 25-29, 2000 (Box 114)
    - New Paltz, Jul 15, 2000 (Box 114)
    - Hawaii, Dec 2000 (Box 114)
    - CH, 2000 (Box 114)
    - UK, 2000 (Box 114)
    - Florida, Feb 2001 (Box 114)
    - Cazenovia, Mar 6, 2001 (Box 114)
    - LA, Mar 31, 2001 (Box 114)
    - New Paltz, Apr 20, 2001 (Box 114)
    - Berlin, Jun 2001 (Box 114)
    - Zurich, Budapest, Berlin, Jun 2001 (Box 114)
    - CH, Jul 25, 2001 (Box 114)
    - CH and BPEST, Jul-Aug 2001 (Box 114)
    - Clearwater, FL, Sep 29, 2001 (Box 114)
    - Soule L., Oct 24, 2001 (Box 114)
    - Szasz Award NYC, Nov 9, 2001 (Box 114)
    - New York, Mar 4, 2002 (Box 114)
    - Michigan, Apr 4-5, 2002 (Box 114)
    - SF, Apr 11-15, 2002 (Box 114)
    - Las Vegas, May 3, 2002 (Box 114)
    - CATO, DC, May 9, 2002 (Box 114)
    - Zurich, Jun 2002 (Box 114)
    - CH, Aug 2002 (Box 114)
    - Florida, Oct 25-27, 2002 (Box 114)
    - Rochester, MI, Nov 2002 (Box 114)
    - LP, New Paltz, Apr 25-27, 2003 (Box 114)
    - CH, May 2003 (Box 114)
    - CH, Jul 2003 (Box 114)
    - CATO, Sep 25, 2003 (Box 114)
    - Louisville, KY, Oct 30, 2003 (Box 114)
    - American-Hungarian F., Nov 11, 2003 (Box 114)
    - Milan, Nov 28, 2003 (Box 114)
    - London, Dec 7, 2003 (Box 114)
    - Travel Requests, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Miscellaneous, 2001-2002; undated (Box 114)
  - Universidad Francisco Marroquin, binder with information about the university, including mention of Szasz's honorary degree (1979) (Box 114)
- Recordings
  - Audiorecordings
    - 1. Blood Sweat & Tears: You Made Me So Very Happy 2. Man of La Mancha, szasz_t_182; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 85)
    - 14th Annual Conference on Alcohol Problems "A Conversation with Dr. Szasz" Thomas Szasz, M.D., May 1992; szasz_t_063; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - 14th Annual Conference on Alcohol Problems "Opening Plenary Session" Thomas Szasz, M.D. Tape 1 of 3, szasz_t_064; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - 14th Annual Conference on Alcohol Problems "Opening Plenary Session" Thomas Szasz, M.D. Tape 2 of 3, May 1992; szasz_t_065; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - 14th Annual Conference on Alcohol Problems "Opening Plenary Session" Thomas Szasz, M.D. Tape 3 of 3, May 1992; szasz_t_066; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - 1985 Evolution Conference National Public Radio Interview, szasz_t_002; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 75)
    - "Autonomous Psychotherapy" 68 A; WS 30, szasz_t_058; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - "A Different View of Mental Illness" Therapeutic State Georgetown University Audio Tape Series, szasz_t_130; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 82)
    - A Glimpse of New Zealand, szasz_t_208; Film: 16mm
    - All in the Mind 7, 09/30/1981; szasz_t_077; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 79)
    - American Holistic Medical Institute "Myth of Psychotherapy" Thomas Szasz, M.D., Jun 1980; szasz_t_123; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 82)
    - "Autonomous Psychotherapy" Thomas Szasz, M.D.; Evolution of Psychotherapy WS 3, 07/31/1994; szasz_t_029; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 75)
    - Bea Roeder, Schizophrenic & Chicano Culture, 05/06/1978; szasz_t_129; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 82)
    - The Birmingham Temple Humanist Forum Presents Dr. Thomas Szasz and Dr. Emanuel Tanay "Debate: The Psychiatrist in the Courtroom: Hero or Hoax", szasz_t_154; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 83)
    - Broffman Trial SOH, 1962; szasz_t_190; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 85)
    - Buckley 2, szasz_t_196; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 86)
    - Can be [lete], szasz_t_193; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 86)
    - "Case Discussion Panel" Bettelheim, Bowen, Goulding, Szasz; The Evolution of Psychotherapy, szasz_t_108; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 81)
    - "Classical Cases in Schizophrenia", side 1: Psychosocial Treatment of Schizophrenia / side 2: Mahler [Volume 4]; szasz_t_090; 1/4 inch audio cassette; running time 00:40:00 (Box 81)
    - "Classical Cases in Schizophrenia", 1988; side 1: The Evolution of Antipsychotic Drug Therapy; side 2: Vivaldi [Volume 4]; szasz_t_092; 1/4 inch audio cassette; running time 00:40:00 (Box 81)
    - "Confidentiality & Privileged Communications", 1972; szasz_t_175; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 83)
      Discussion features Richard C. Allen, J.D., Prof. of Law, Geo. Wash. U.; Jonas R. Rappeport, M.D., Assoc. Clinical Prof., U. of Md.; Maj. Harvey L. Ruben, M.D. Office of the Surgeon Gen’l., U.S. Army; Thomas S. Szasz, M.D. Prof. of Psychiatry, State U. Hosp., Syracuse, N.Y.. Discussion is moderated by Roger Grimsby, INFO A Business Information Service for Physicians.
    - "Conversation with an Officially Denominated ‘Schizophrenic' Patient" Thomas, Szasz, M.D.; The Evolution of Psychotherapy, szasz_t_097; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 81)
    - "Conversation with an Officially Denominated ‘Schizophrenic' Patient" Thomas, Szasz, M.D.; The Evolution of Psychotherapy, szasz_t_098; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 81)
    - Copia II T.S. Szasz Conversazione con T.S.S. Registrara A Zurigo IL In Occasione Del I Congresso Del Comitato DiRitti Dell'Vomo, 06/28/1981; szasz_t_100; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 81)
    - “Critical Reflections on Metaphor Madness and Medicine” by Thomas Szasz / Thomas Szasz Conference: “The Lunatic, The Loves and the Port” Niagara Falls, Jan 19-21, 1979; szasz_t_172; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 83)
    - Fundamentals of Strategic Therapy Cloe Madanes, Lic. Psychol., Thomas Szasz, M.D. D 8, 07/31/1994; szasz_t_032; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 75)
    - Dan Desole, M.D., interviews “Schizophrenic” Annie; ‘Consulting Other Patients’; DeSole Sums Up Case, 1994; szasz_t_167; DVD (Box 84)